class Questions {
  static List<Map<String, dynamic>> quizData = [
    {
      'id': '1',
      'question': 'What is Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'A type of musical instrument',
      'optionTwo': 'A database management system',
      'optionThree': 'A programming language developed by Google',
      'optionFour': 'An operating system',
      'correctAnswer': 'A programming language developed by Google',
    },
    {
      'id': '2',
      'question': 'What is the main purpose of Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'To build mobile applications',
      'optionTwo': 'To create web applications',
      'optionThree': 'To develop server-side applications',
      'optionFour': 'To design user interfaces',
      'correctAnswer': 'To build mobile applications',
    },
    {
      'id': '3',
      'question': 'Which of the following is true about Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'It is a statically-typed language',
      'optionTwo': 'It is based on the Java programming language',
      'optionThree': 'It only supports single-threaded execution',
      'optionFour': 'It is primarily used for data analysis',
      'correctAnswer': 'It is a statically-typed language',
    },
    {
      'id': '4',
      'question': 'What is the keyword used to define a variable in Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'let',
      'optionTwo': 'var',
      'optionThree': 'const',
      'optionFour': 'final',
      'correctAnswer': 'var',
    },
    {
      'id': '5',
      'question': 'What does the "async" keyword indicate in Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'The function returns a Future',
      'optionTwo': 'The function is synchronous',
      'optionThree': 'The function is a generator',
      'optionFour': 'The function is an event handler',
      'correctAnswer': 'The function returns a Future',
    },
    {
      'id': '6',
      'question': 'Which collection in Dart allows duplicate values?',
      'optionOne': 'Map',
      'optionTwo': 'Set',
      'optionThree': 'List',
      'optionFour': 'Queue',
      'correctAnswer': 'List',
    },
    {
      'id': '7',
      'question': 'How do you add an element to the end of a List in Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'list.add(element)',
      'optionTwo': 'list.insert(element)',
      'optionThree': 'list.append(element)',
      'optionFour': 'list.push(element)',
      'correctAnswer': 'list.add(element)',
    },
    {
      'id': '8',
      'question':
          'What is the output of the following Dart code snippet?\n\nvar x = 5;\nvar y = x++;\nprint(y);',
      'optionOne': '4',
      'optionTwo': '5',
      'optionThree': '6',
      'optionFour': 'Error',
      'correctAnswer': '5',
    },
    {
      'id': '9',
      'question': 'How do you perform string interpolation in Dart?',
      'optionOne': "'Hello, \$name!'",
      'optionTwo': "'Hello, {name}!'",
      'optionThree': "'Hello, %name!'",
      'optionFour': "'Hello, #name!'",
      'correctAnswer': "'Hello, \$name!'",
    },
    {
      'id': '10',
      'question': 'What does the "is" keyword do in Dart?',
      'optionOne': 'It checks if an object is an instance of a specific type',
      'optionTwo': 'It checks if two objects are equal',
      'optionThree': 'It performs bitwise operations on integers',
      'optionFour': 'It checks if a string is empty',
      'correctAnswer':
          'It checks if an object is an instance of a specific type',
    },
  ];
}
